oilandgaspeople.com 2019-11-30

# Privacy

## **Summary**

This summarises the key points of our privacy policy. For more information, read our full privacy policy below.

### **Use of Cookies**

This site uses cookies to store information on your computer.

Some cookies on this site are essential, and the site won't work as expected without them. These cookies are set when you submit a form, login or interact with the site by doing something that goes beyond clicking on simple links.

We also use some non-essential cookies to anonymously track visitors or enhance your experience of the site. If you\'re not happy with this, we won\'t set these cookies but some nice features of the site may be unavailable.

To control third party cookies, you can also adjust your [browser settings](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

### **Personal information collected**

We collect information:

  * When you register an account to become an Oil and Gas People user (“User”), such as your name, e-mail, country, location, occupation and a password.
  * When you add to your profile with further information about yourself or your private contacts
  * We use cookies and other technologies to recognize you and customize your experience.
  * We automatically receive from your internet use such information as your IP address, the URLs of sites from which you arrive or leave the Oil and Gas People website, your type of browser and your ISP.

### **Uses of personal information**

We use the information you provide to:

  * Administer your account with us and customize the service we provide to you.
  * To send you service or promotional communications through email and notices on the Oil and Gas People website.
  * We do not sell, rent or otherwise provide your personal identifiable information to any third parties for marketing purposes although we will share your information with carefully selected partners offering services that complement those offered by Oil and Gas People.
  * We provide you with the means to control whether or not your contact information is shared with recruiters and on the public domain.
  * In order to deliver our services, we may share information with third parties. For example, to process payments made by you, we share some of your information with the credit card processing company we use.
  * Enable you to share your information and communicate with other users.

### **Your information choices**

You can:

  * Review, enhance or edit your personal information through your personal profile page.
  * Choose what information you make available through your public profile.
  * Control the messages you receive from Oil and Gas People and other Users and how these messages are sent.
  * Tell us to close your Oil and Gas People account.

### **Important information**

Notice of all changes that materially affect ways in which your personal information may be used or shared will be posted in updates to our Privacy Policy.

Oil and Gas People is registered with the Information Commissioners Office (ICO).

### **Security**

Personal information you provide will be secured with industry standards and technology.

### **How to contact us**

If you have any questions or comments please email us at [info@oilandgaspeople.com](mailto:info@oilandgaspeople.com)

## **Our Full Privacy Policy**

Your privacy is our top concern. We work hard to earn and keep your trust, so we adhere to the following principles to protect your privacy:

  * We do not rent or sell your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes.
  * We do not share your contact information with another User without your consent.
  * Any personally identifiable information that you provide will be secured with industry standard protocols and technology.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. By continuing to use the Oil and Gas People service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on the Oil and Gas People website, you are consenting to the changes.

Please read this privacy policy to learn more about:

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours is collected by Oil and Gas People?
  2. How the information is used.
  3. With whom the information may be shared.
  4. How you can access and change your Account settings.
  5. What security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information collected by Oil and Gas People
  6. How to contact us.
  7. Personal information collected

The purpose of the Oil and Gas People website is to permit Users to voluntarily provide information about themselves for the purposes of job seeking. You willingly provide us certain personal information, which we collect in order to allow you to benefit from the Oil and Gas People website. If you have any hesitation about providing such information to us and/or having such information displayed on the Oil and Gas People website or otherwise used in any manner permitted in this Privacy Policy, you should not become a member of Oil and Gas People.

We collect your personal information in the following ways:

### **Registration**

In order to become a User, you must first create an account on our website. To create an account you are required to provide the following contact information, which you recognize and expressly acknowledge is personal information allowing others, including Oil and Gas People, to identify your: name, email address, country, ZIP/postal code, a brief summary of your professional background, and a password chosen by you.

### **Profile Information**

Once you become a User, you may provide additional information in the Profile section describing your skills, professional experiences, employment history, employment documents and other information related to your career. Any information you provide at registration or in the Profile section that is not personally identifiable may be used in the same manner and extent to which other information that is not personally identifiable is permitted to be used hereunder, including for the purpose of serving advertisements through the service.

All candidates edited profiles will be fully visible and searchable to anyone using the site. These edited profiles will contain general information relating to work history, qualifications, location, experience, availability and training certificates. These profiles will not contain candidate’s names, contact details, date of birth or their current employment position.  
Candidates can link to their edited profiles using a standard URL. Edited profiles will be indexed by search engines. Oil and Gas People cannot control the content of third party websites. Changes you make to your profile whether editing it or deleting it may take some time to reflect in 3rd party sites.   
Candidates have the option once registered to link to a full version of their profile. This special URL should only be sent to trusted sources and is intended to be used to allow selected recruiters access to your full profile for free. We do not recommend this URL be used in the public domain to link to your profile from websites, social networks, blogs etc. Any person or company you choose to send this link to will have full access to your profile, all contact details and any certificates or documents you have chosen to upload to Oil and Gas People. The difference between the 2 link types is further explained from within the relevant pages of Oil and Gas People.

### **How we share your information with recruiters.**

We give our users full control over their personal details. When you build a profile on Oil and Gas People you have some choices that allow you to decide how much of your information will be available to recruiters using our site.

From your control panel you have the option to turn profile privacy on or off. Profiles with privacy turned off allow recruiters to access all the information contained within your profile. This includes personal information, contact details, any documents uploaded to the site and all of your employment history and work preferences.

Recruiters with full access to our site will be able to access this information on any candidate while recruiters with limited or Pay per Match access will be required to pay a fee before your contact details are released.

With profile privacy switched on, your edited profile will be all that recruiters can see until you confirm you want to give them access to your contact details. This confirmation will be provided in the form of an automatic email recruiters can send you with details on a specific position they are recruiting for. Such requests will be sent to your email through the Oil and Gas People system without your email address being released to the recruiter. Only once you click on the ‘confirm an interest’ link within the email will recruiters be able to see your contact details. If you state you are not interested your details will remain hidden. Recruiters are able to view the status of each request made from within their control panel. 

By applying directly for a position listed on Oil and Gas People you are confirming that the recruiter may see your contact details and have access to your full profile.

All recruiters signing up to the site are verified in accordance with our own procedures, we verify each company manually to ensure as far as is reasonably practicable that all recruiters using our site are genuine and that their intentions are in accordance with the services we provide. We also monitor the use of such accounts for suspicious or irregular activity and will take any action required to protect candidates from fraudulent attempts to access their data.

### **Customer Service**

Oil and Gas People may collect information on your site usage to improve our services and to provide a high level of customer service. We offer a live support feature through our contact page that allows recruiters or candidates to contact our support team in real time. This service is not available 24hours; instead candidates can contact us using the feedback links or contact forum on the contact page. As an internet based company we do not offer telephone support through our site but we are happy to get in contact with site users by this means if necessary.

### **Cookies**

Like most websites, Oil and Gas People uses cookies and web log files to track site usage. A cookie is a tiny data file which resides on your computer which allows Oil and Gas People to recognize you as a User when you return to the Oil and Gas People website using the same computer and web browser. If your browser settings do not allow cookies, you may not be able to use the Oil and Gas People website. Like the information you enter at registration or in your Profile, cookie and log file data is used to customize your experience on our website.

We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing User preferences and tracking User trends. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. Unfortunately, if your browser settings do not allow cookies or you opt to refuse all cookies, you may not be able to use the Oil and Gas People website or services. Oil and Gas People does not store personally identifiable information in the cookies.

### **Log files, IP addresses and information about your computer**

Due to the communications standards on the Internet, when you visit the Oil and Gas People web site we automatically receive the URL of the site from which you came and the site to which you are going when you leave Oil and Gas People. We also receive the Internet protocol (IP) address of your computer (or the proxy server you use to access the World Wide Web), your computer operating system and type of web browser you are using, email patterns, as well as the name of your ISP. This information is used to analyze overall trends to help us improve the Oil and Gas People service. The linkage between your IP address and your personally identifiable information is not shared with third-parties without your permission or except when required by law.

### **Sharing Information with Third Parties**

Oil and Gas People takes the privacy of Users very seriously. We do not sell, rent, or otherwise provide your personally identifiable information to third parties for marketing purposes. We will only share your personally identifiable information with third parties to carry out your instructions or to provide specific services or information. For instance, we may use a credit card processing company to bill Users for additional services. These third parties do not retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services and they are bound by confidentiality agreements which limit their use of such information. Candidates are not charged for registering or using Oil and Gas People but we do offer 3rd party services from our toolkit, some of which may incur a charge. These are additional services and users will be given clear choices as to whether they use them or not.

Oil and Gas People offers a “public profile” feature which allows Users to publish their full Oil and Gas People profile on the internet by means of a link. Users may choose not to use this feature. However any links posted would continue to give access until deleted or removed. Oil and Gas People does not warrant how often third-party search engines will update their cache.

### **Legal Disclaimer**

It is possible that we may need to disclose personal information when required by law, such as responses to civil or criminal subpoenas, or other requests by law enforcement personnel. We will disclose such information wherein we have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, subpoena, or other legal process or request to Oil and Gas People brought in any country throughout the world, or to exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

### **You’re Information Choices**

_Accessing and Changing Your Account Information_  
You can review the personal information you provided us and make any desired changes to the information you publish, or to the settings for your Oil and Gas People account including your email, and contact preferences, at any time by logging in to your account on the Oil and Gas People website.

### **Important Information**

**Children**  
Children are not eligible to use our service and we ask that minors (under the age of 18) do not submit any personal information to us or use the service.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
Oil and Gas People may update this privacy policy at any time, with or without advance notice. In the event there are significant changes in the way we treat your personally identifiable information, we will display a notice on the Oil and Gas People website or send you an email, as provided for above. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Policy applies to all information that we have about you and your account.  
If you use the Oil and Gas People service after notice of changes have been sent to you or published on our site, you hereby provide your consent to the changed practices.

**Further Information**  
Oil and Gas People Recruitment LTD is a registered LTD Company based in the UK.

Oil and Gas People is registered with the Information Commissioners Office (ICO).

**Security**  
In order to secure your personal information, access to your data on Oil and Gas People is password-protected, and sensitive data (such as credit card information) is protected by SSL encryption when it is exchanged between your web browser and the Oil and Gas People website. To protect any data you store on our servers we also regularly audit our system for possible vulnerabilities and attacks and we use a tier-one secured-access data centre. It is your responsibility to protect the security of your login information.

If you have questions or comments about this privacy policy, please email us at [info@oilandgaspeople.com](mailto:info@oilandgaspeople.com) or contact us from the contact us page either using the form or live support service.

This website is owned and operated by Oil and Gas People Recruitement Ltd. For more information please email info@oilandgaspeople.com or call 02034685540
